Nicole: CPD refers to the process
of developing, maintaining and also
documenting your skills, knowledge
and experience within your profession
and throughout your career.
Abraham: CPD can be a structured
process to help ensure that standards
are kept high and consistent.
It allows for greater commitment
and engagement and the sharing
of best practice and support
across an organisation.
Nicole: CPD may be conducted internally
or by external specialist companies
who can deliver specific training.
Abraham: In cyber security, CPD
is very important as the threat
landscape is constantly changing.
Many professionals find it hard
to stay on top of their roles,
whilst keeping up to date with new
techniques and malware being developed.
Nicole: This is why employers should
always set time aside for regular
CPD training even for their top
professionals and not just rely on
employees to keep their knowledge
up to date, on their own time.
Abraham: Cyber security teams in
turn can also deliver CPD training
to all other staff to help keep
an organisation safe and secure.
Nicole: As well as regular structured CPD
training, cyber security professionals
should look to other ways of keeping up
to date with their industry knowledge.
There is no one way of doing
this and there are many sources
that can offer information both
technical and news oriented.
Abraham: Technology websites and
magazines may cover aspects of
security on a regular basis, so it
is worthwhile for those involved in
cyber security to know where to look
for the most up to date information.
Sites such as NCSC, Wired, Computer
Weekly The Hacker News, etc.
It’s worth checking out their websites!
Nicole: There are also many companies
that sell security software to home and
business users who also regularly update
their websites with emerging security
threats and how to overcome them.
Abraham: But remember their
main aim is to sell software!
Nicole: Many security professionals
have their own blogs or websites,
but you should be careful
that they are legitimate.
Abraham: As a cyber security professional,
you will probably get to interact with
others in your field meeting them at
training sessions, conferences or online.
Building up a network is time
consuming but a great way to share
information as well as helping
tomove forward your career.
You never know who is
looking for new employees!
Nicole: Social media can sometimes
be helpful if you know where to
find specific forums for cyber
security news and information but
should not be always relied on!
Abraham: Educating yourself on the dark
web can also give up to date information
on what malware is available and what
organisations have recently been hacked.
Nicole: And finally, there are the
good old face to face as well as
online cyber security events such as
conferences, lectures, discussions,
workshops, networking events,
educational courses and boot camps.
Abraham: These may cost to attend but
employers will often have a budget to
cover these especially when used for CPD.
Nicole: Cyber security and the threat
landscape are constantly changing and CPD
is an important way to keep up to date
with all the changes and keep pace with
new emerging threats and new technologies.
Abraham: Cyber security teams who fail
to keep up to date or fall behind with
their CPD, leave themselves open to
coming a victim of the latest attack
and leave their organisation vulnerable.
Nicole: On a personal level CPD can help
you grow and develop your professional
career, but it can also help those
you work for, to benefit from the
information and new skills you gain.
Abraham: Further learning can
significantly improve your knowledge
and skills and can often help to
meet regulatory requirements for
your organisation, but don’t just
think of CPD as something you have
to do, embrace the opportunity.
Nicole: Also remember to let your employer
know how further training for you, can
help everyone, as you can disseminate
that information and help to keep
the whole organisation cyber secure.